

# Sepehr SeifiZarei

- Turku, Finland
- +358 414736098
- sepehr.seifizarei@utu.fi
- sepehrseifizarei.github.io
- 🚺 github.com/sepehrseifizarei
- in linkedin.com/in/sepehrseifizarei

# About Me \_\_\_\_

I am a dedicated researcher in health technology, focusing on machine learning and data science. My work aims to advance unobtrusive monitoring systems for cardiovascular diseases, blending technical expertise with a passion for improving healthcare outcomes.

## Education

#### Doctor of Technology in Computer Science - Health Technology 2023 - Present

University of Turku (UTU), Turku, Finland

Thesis: Unobtrusive Physiological Monitoring and Diagnosis of Cardiovascular Diseases

using Machine Learning

Supervisors: Assistant Prof. Matti Kaisti, Associate Prof. Antti Airola

#### Master of Science in Biomedical Engineering - Bioelectric 2018 - 2022

Iran University of Science and Technology (IUST), Tehran, Iran

**GPA:** 4/4 - 17.42/20

Thesis: Despeckling of Medical Ultrasound Images using Deep Learning

Supervisor: Associate Prof. Hamid Behnam

#### Bachelor of Science in Electrical Engineering - Electronics 2013 - 2018

Bu-Ali Sina University (BASU), Hamedan, Iran

**GPA:** 3.5/4 - 16.5/20

Thesis: Application of FibroScan® device in liver diseases

Supervisor: Prof. Soheil Ganjefar

# **Work Experience**

Doctoral Researcher RM4Health: Algorithm development and heart failure investigation, 2023-Present,

University of Turku

Moore4Medical: Signal processing and atrial fibrillation detection using radar and bed

sensors, 2022-2023, University of Turku

Teaching Assistant Medical Instrumentation: ECG and PPG circuit simulation with LT Spice software and

hands-on implementation, Spring 2024, University of Turku

Physiology Lab: ECG signal acquisition and processing with LabChart software,

2019-2020, Iran University of Science and Technology

Internship Electrical motors fault diagnosis, 2015-2016, Hamedan Technical Electric

#### Skills

Programming Languages: Python, MATLAB

**Deep Learning Frameworks:** Keras, Tensorflow, PyTorch

Cloud and Tools: AWS, GitHub, Linux

Data Science: Data Analytics, Data Visualization, Cluster Computing (CSC-PUHTI) Software: AutoCAD, Altium, Onshape, Proteus Design Suite, Code Vision AVR

Markup Language: LATEX, HTML/CSS

### **Publications**

#### Conference

• S. Seifizarei et al, "Evaluating Piezoelectric Ballistocardiography for Post-Surgical Heart Rate Monitoring.", Computing in Cardiology 2024

### Journal

• S. Seifizarei et al, "Continuous Radar-based Heart Rate Monitoring in Intensive Care Unit .", IEEE Journal of Biomedical and Health Informatics

### In preparation

• S. Seifizarei et al, "Robust Multi-node Accelerometer-Based Bed Monitoring System for Longitudinal Heart Rate Detection in Clinical Setting.", Target Journal: JMIR mHealth and uHealth

# **Projects**

#### Graduate

## Statistical Pattern Recognition (GPA: 4/4 - 18.65/20)

- · Under supervision of Prof. Mohammadreza Daliri
- Final Project: ECG arrhythmia classification using a 2D convolutional neural network for Electrocardiogram (ECG)

# Medical Image Processing (GPA: 4/4 - 16.1/20)

- Under supervision of Assistant Prof. Aboozar Ghaffari
- Final Project: A Hierarchical Image Matting Model for Blood Vessel Segmentation in Fundus Images

# Awards and Honors \_

- Received national graduate and undergraduate full scholarship
- Ranked within top 5% among more than 40,000 participants in Iranian university entrance exam for Master's degree
- Ranked within top 1% among more than 222,000 participants in Iranian university entrance exam for Bachelor's degree
- 2nd Rank in Handball national universities competitions 2018

## Research Interest \_

- Health Technology
- · Data Science
- Machine Learning
- · Deep Learning

## Language Proficiency

· Persian: Native

• English: Fluent (TOEFL: 105/120)

· Finnish: Basic

# **Voluntary work**

• Member of Hamedan Animals Rescue Non-governmental Organization, Hamedan, Iran, 2018-Present

#### **Hobbies and Interests**

Sport

- Cycling
- Handball
- · Ping-Pong

#### Music

- Piano
- African Drum